guys today is a really happy day for me
an old friend and a collaborator both
professionally as well as personally is
back in studio executive director at
Isis lumbar General Insurance company uh
the one around the Sanjeev mantri so
wonderful to see you how are you looking
sharp as always thank you so much Rishi
for having me here it's been a long time
since we have caught up physically uh an
absolute pleasure I think meeting you
gives me a lot of energy so I'm really
loving it being here you know it's the
reason all of you were listening is that
we are now in the seventh season of get
some sun Asia Lombard presents get some
sun on radio one which is a travel
program and actually because of the
pandemic we had a breather so my
association with Sanjeev and with icsa
Lombard and radio one's partnership goes
back seven years
so five years of the show seven years in
all and during this time I think we
definitely as Radio One have grown uh
and your collaboration has really helped
us given us some very valuable valuable
insights
I'd like you to view this Association no
absolutely Rishi I still remember very
distinctly almost seven years back when
this discussion came up with respect to
having traveled getting spoken only on
audio mode which is through radio
it sounded a bit off you know it was
kind of making us believe how does it
work out how will we be having an
audience which will get convinced that
we can talk about it the multiple
factors which goes to the credit of you
and your team in terms of making a
reality one is getting star I think the
our sutures have always been there for
last five years and we've seen was a
Pioneer thing to do and over the last
few years the way the show has evolved
and the insights that get created which
are curated for the listeners have been
tremendous
from our side I think something which
you were relatively averse to what we
have pushed you hard is on the digital
side you've been a radio man the voice
was good enough but we wanted everyone
to know and have a look on how smart
rishiki looks so you've got ourselves on
the digital side with you we have pushed
you one critical element I think which
we have brought together in which I'm
sure the listeners are enjoying the
influencers
every category is experts and it's
always far more you know you're far more
aligned to accepting the views when an
expert says it than an ordinary person
and by getting Travel Experts talk about
their experiences when what to do and
what not to do
we've added all that is required for our
listeners and that I think together with
the team of radio one as well as us it's
been a privilege and we believe that we
have places to go one in terms of travel
another in terms of the property that is
there over here you know there's a
magical Resurgence in travel it's almost
as though people were frustrated sitting
at home during the pandemic some had
saved money others had you know suddenly
shifted their priorities because they
realized anything can happen anytime how
do you think the international travel
Market will grow in the next few years
very uh interesting and pertinent
question uh we all will agree to the
fact that barring last few months we had
a very difficult couple of years full of
uncertainty and there uncertainty can be
a multiple casit and you can have a
global financial crisis you're worried
your wealth gets eroded but when it
becomes personal and becomes a power of
one in terms of our own health getting
impacted your family health getting
impacted it's got severe repercussions
uh someone would have told us if it has
seen a movie where everyone's sitting
indoors for months together not moving
it was hard to believe right we could
have felt this is not going to happen
and that all got enacted as it was a
difficult phase international travel
well Percy I think is coming back to the
Revenge travel world that we word that
keeps coming up for discussion has
become a reality we have seen a huge
search and there are some interesting
statistics in terms of how the growth of
travel is coming back and I use
insurance as a proxy because that's
where I understand the most to explain
you where is the momentum coming from
the travel insurance Market which is
just about fraction and I'll talk that
in a bit uh it's relatively on the lower
side was around 800 crores and
thereabouts when we talk about March of
19 which is that full Financial year so
and from there in March of 20 it
remained in the same Zone flatish we had
pandemic coming probably somewhere early
stages in the month of March and then
for March the next financial year it
moved to just 250 crores so you can see
the
the lockdown impact the global shutdown
on multiple counts took the market down
we never thought that this will persist
even longer March of 22 which is another
Financial admit too it went to 450
crores in there above still from the
peak of 820 850 close it was 450 but if
you look at the stats of the year that I
just got close March of 23 Financial
year
it's almost 13 000 crores so we are 20
plus on the overall travel this speaks
about the fact that life has come back
to normal and even gone beyond as far as
travel is concerned another interesting
stat if I have to speak about in terms
of what's happening and are people more
aware when they talk about insurance and
I think that is a pertinent piece and I
won't really listeners to think about it
in March of 19 totally as per the
figures available the three crore 30
million International tickets got used
but the number of total travel insurance
policies that got sold
were just 2.6 2.7 million so the fact is
that in that particular stage in less
than 10 percent people were buying
travel insurance now to me this is
completely bizarre because there were
challenges and mind you when the
pandemic happened people got trapped
overseas people with insurance
there's so much at ease because the
medical requirement the longevity that
was there because they had to extend
their travel flights got canceled all of
it got taken care of
so clearly what is evident is that the
penetration was very low we expected a
significant search
when people go people are aware of the
risk that is associated but somehow
the ability to visualize that will
devolve or still on the lower side now
that being said we have seen a surge of
20 25 percent to me that is still not
enough if there are listeners talking
about it make sure if you're traveling
please get yourself insured it's not
about icsl Lombard it's about you buy it
from wherever you want to but do not
take a step outside country without
getting a travel insurance because you
are risking a lot more than you can
imagine
that's very well put you know I actually
want to quote from uh something you have
said in a past interview and it's a very
interesting comment and you have said
Rishi no matter how much fun you want to
have you can make it even more fun by
taking care of all the logistics well in
advance before you start traveling which
again sparked an idea for us we said
every year we make ranveer Singh talk
about travel destinations where to go
what to do you know the experiential
aspect of it and this time when we
started negotiations and you know
discussing creative options with his
team I said why can't we do seven tools
of travel you know and that has really
shattered the roof you know ranveer
Singh talking about tools of travel or
the logistics of it influencers coming
on and talking about the tools of travel
and the logistics of it so it's not as
though you magically appear on a Greece
island or magically go on to the uh you
know the Pharaohs of Egypt and the
swings there's so many of those
Logistics that need to be taken care of
before so you that must make you very
happy that even the program now is
focused on the tools apart from just the
experience I think clearly when the
seventh season of get some sun you're
talking about seven tools in terms of
and seven has it got it got its own
value seven well we talk about seven
continents you're talking seven C so
there is so much magical things spread
around and the fact that you have
Incorporated multiple aspects and there
are a lot of conversation that you
happen with your own friends and they
speak about it that I don't like I like
to be adventurous you know and I want to
do things impromptu unplanned basis I'm
saying this is absolutely fair but you
will not climb on Everest without proper
clothings right so there is there is
that element of precaution that comes so
that you can actually live in the moment
and enjoy because you have been prepared
so these aspects should be addressed and
some of the angularities which have got
covered and the insights that we shared
and for that matter I think who else is
better than our own Rockstar when he
speaks about it there's so much of
conviction to me he's done all he's been
around he knows even someone like him
who's taken care of goes through those
uncertain phase and mind you in terms of
ill health in terms of accident it does
not distinguish in personalities it
comes on a flatter curve to everyone so
prepared being prepared I think is a
must and it makes absolute sense in
terms of what radio one team has done to
cover across the season thanks a lot you
know you gave us an overview of the
current state of India's international
travel insurance Market you said that
you know you want to push the envelope
more
but in that aspect are there any other
Trends you'd like to share with us and
how ICICI Lombard GIC is preparing to
face those strings
the trends are ominous you know if you
talk about medical inflation ah whether
you look at domestically or
internationally it's hit the roof a very
interesting place typically uh there's a
frequency by which we judge as to what
the claim stuff so if you have done 100
policies uh what is the frequency with
the claim comes uh in covet uh that
frequency went up by almost 75 to 100 so
that was the level of extrapolation if
ordinarily speaking you see a hundred
traveling uh you know individuals will
have three to four of them claiming it
went to almost six to seven in that
period bulk of the claim started coming
from in-house hospitalization we saw
that there was a hundred percent
increase on a court of covet claim the
world itself was settling in in terms of
what protocols to follow uh how they
will you know that there was no defined
way in which the treatment could be
administered there were flight
disruptions there was extension of stay
all of those expenses that come people
who were insured we could step in and do
what is required another good part is
when you take travel insurance for
reputed company in a way they can step
in and do what is required to address
the need we provide internationally
cashless now that's a significant
because if I go there I go with limited
funds to take care of the holiday I
don't carry fund for the exigency and if
you're hospitalized
how do you manage that cash flow and it
can become a nightmare and clearly from
an India perspective you have seen lot
more aspiring middle class which has
started traveling and that traffic is
expected to go up and away
it's important that this is understood
upfront and I'll give a simple example
to make my point typically you end up
getting cover of half a million pounds
but there are categories available below
that
the lower one which is a half of that
half a million two and a half 2.5 in the
cover which I'm talking about two and a
half lakh dollars comes at a price of
2500 rupees if you buy a 5 lakh which is
half a million dollar cover you got to
pay probably 3200 rupees you are talking
of an incremental rupees of 700 but
invariably when people are booking the
travel insurance they say let me buy the
lower one
and to do a evacuation if you have to
come on an air ambulance back to India
for your treatment that cost itself and
go to 75 to 80 000 and post that you
have to also take care of the medical
expense that comes in this is a very
common sensical uh you know requirements
which can be addressed and there's no
reason to be pennified spawn fully I
mean what is a 3400 to 4000 rupees
expense in context of your travel
overseas where you will end up blowing
far higher this penetration of 10 to 12
percent also which I spoke about Rishi
is hard to consume we need to make
people aware and what is it that we are
talking about awareness versus ability
awareness is reasonably there the last
few years that we have lived with have
made us all believe there are challenges
that can come up it can disrupt our best
late plans and now comes ability if
you're traveling you can 100 percent
afford this kind of an expense it's just
that
you know I am not vulnerable and that
creates the mess
you know one doesn't say that you you
should be an island onto yourself
any uh you know insurance provider today
has obviously got to keep a Keen Eye on
competition
and I think I say Lombard GIC has
retained its Innovation and at the same
time stayed one step ahead of the
competition
how do you differentiate your travel
insurance products from those of
competitors in the market how important
is that to you ah yes of course so there
are enough and more players who are
there in the space but clearly if we
come out as the leaders we're probably
uh one out of five travel insurance
policies that is getting sold is being
picked up by icsl Lombard uh obviously
we have done what is required uh to
serve our customers far more
appropriately at all points of time uh
in terms of features cashless which I've
already spoken about it hire some
insured no Clauses within Clauses which
can deny you a claim or ability to
handle uh this is a problem somewhere
else and you you need help at the
domestic level that kind of a cover is
available loss passport lost baggage
whichever element that you're talking of
is taken care of in Terms of uh the The
Travelers need that comes into play uh
also the digital solutioning your
ability to intimate claims digitally and
close the whole process digitally
purchase of course it's not us all
others also do a seamless option of
going on the website and picking up see
one thing which has come out very
clearly is that the faceless part and
ensuring the service comes in gone are
the days when you always felt the need
of having an agent whom you can call and
speak with the younger generation the
billionaires which are becoming part of
the traveling mass for the country are
very very comfortable doing this all of
us have a lined up processes to the hilt
to ensure that we deliver them Best in
Class service and one appropriate thing
which has to be understood is when you
service any customer through technology
you don't differentiate between classes
and masses yeah I mean for an ATM
withdrawal each one of us has to stand
the line and do a withdrawal if I go to
the cash counter they can be a
differentiated treatment so technology
in a way ensures that we all are treated
fairly at a particular price and to May
well sir that's a very big plus that
comes and can give any middle class
person like us confidence that I'll be
taken care of in case of an accident
that democratization if I can call it
that is this is spectacular very very
well said okay uh you know I I look at
these constant Innovations in terms of
product launches in terms of How It's
enhancing the life of the in short
person and I'm going to ask you to
reflect on a couple of them you recently
launched anywhere cashless Innovative
product tell us more about it how does
it work
now this is one of the first of its kind
that we have put across the Shia and I'm
very happy to connect with my listeners
and tell you uh typically in a
conventional process we all have Network
hospitals we tie off with them and in
the case of an Excellency where you're
going to be an impatient impatient where
you're getting admitted in the hospital
uh in network we do a cashless
settlement but over the last few years
we realized that many of our customers
who are far-flung who've got uh you know
who have to go to hospital which is not
part of an empanel hospital with us used
to struggle and used to make claims on a
reimbursement basis at the point of time
when you have to make that payment and
the expense can go to one and a half two
lakhs it's not fair that that kind of a
cash flow is available and where they
end up paying and then sending the whole
process of you know invoices coming to
us and we're reimbursing it that's why
we have taken the Bold step of saying
there is a company we will give you any
time anywhere cashless
we all you need to do is intimate us
that you will be getting admitted even
if that is not part of our Network as an
icsl Lombard customer we will get in
touch with the hospital confirm that
that there will be a cashless settlement
and close your payment without impacting
your cash flow
this to me is a landmark change in terms
of what we have done we have given
freedom to our customers across the
country to enjoy the product and also
don't care bear in their mind that if
they have to only you know reach out to
a network hospital and get the treatment
so it's a big freedom uh that we have
given and this is the key differentiator
wonderful then we move on to the I'll
take care app that's getting some rave
reviews Sanjeev and uh I'd like you to
throw some light on it okay it's again a
classic one uh I must tell the listeners
that we've got almost 5 million
downloads but that's not what the key
data that I'm talking about what is more
important is that almost 30 percent of
the people who are using this app are
not our customers but they are still
using it because the facilities that are
available
one of the key one which is there is
that face scan
any one of our customer non-customer can
get download the app do face scan and in
two minutes they'll get reading the
stress levels the blood pressure the
pulsate the oxidation level all of those
readings can come to them available in a
jiffy on their top and the data will
keep getting stored for their own
reference we also have ensured that
through that I'll take care app
people can make claims raise their
queries you will be surprised that
almost 60 percent of our reimbursement
claims are done people less by people
sending documents through the app
not only this we have a special feature
which is called Dynamic health risk
assessment feature
when I say Dynamic it can real time pick
data from your mobile and as you are
exercising if you're taking more steps
keep changing your profile on it you can
take that particular questionnaire you
will get an assessment of where you are
which stage you are when it comes to
your own Fitness and drive yourself to
the next level because to me
I think your own Fitness becomes one of
the most critical criteria in terms of
ensuring that you are near India ones
are taken care of so this particular app
is more respect to service our customer
end to end and the response that we have
got from customers as well as
non-customers have been truly heartening
you know I want to come back to
something we we talked about a little
earlier and suddenly come back to me
which is customers changing needs in the
international travel insurance Market
really made a very valid point that our
parents generation even you know we a
couple of decades ago we used to feel
very happy saying the insurance agent
has come if it is life insurance or you
know some representative of the company
has come home and a cup of tea
Millennials just don't have the time you
know which is why they love interacting
with technology now artificial
intelligence is here you know you
already adopted bits of it uh at a very
early stage
the fact that these changing needs are
going to always be there
I get the feeling that being in the kind
of business that you are you have to
also read consumers behavior patterns
yes absolutely absolutely and you know
map those Behavior patterns and
sometimes those Behavior patterns change
after 100 years 100 that must be very
exciting part of your job it's exciting
and the way we have done is we want to
use technology with respect to means to
an end but technology with a human touch
see fundamentally uh
Tech processes while they can operate
with very fair amount of you know equal
survey but in the end an emotional touch
is also required so as an organization
we have been very cautious we've used
wherever required of physical process if
we need to we will reach out to the
customers because sometimes a message is
not enough maybe a call is required so
there's a combination so we're very
conscious of the fact that the balance
has to be managed so typically
fulfillment will be done
by using technology but the service
aspect the software part of it is
something which we are also very
cautious of so we have been mixing both
of it from a trend perspective you're
clearly right uh the the like look at
the travel people use the word Revenge
travel now people travel for this is a
sleep holiday people want to travel for
only Adventure Sport I mean there is
there is so much of the wellness travel
just people go on a two weeks or just to
get themselves purified in terms of
getting themselves feeling lighter and
these Trends and probably as you see the
Indian middle class growing by leaps and
Brown these kind of requirements will
keep coming up uh to and to us it's been
a huge journey and I believe that in
next three to five years the overseas
Travelers would probably double from
where we are now so there's a huge
uh you know outflow of passengers that
will happen every year and that's one
part of it we're talking about
international travel there's a domestic
part of it I mean the amount of
investment the government is doing so in
this budget almost 2400 crore has been
put aside to ensure that we beef up our
domestic travel and to me travel can be
a backbone of lot of uh countries the
contribution of travel industry per se
rise in the range of eight to nine
percent of the GDP for us I think it can
grow much faster the way we are
investing as a country and this
contribution can go to 12 to 14 percent
next three to five years that's
wonderful in fact it reminds me in one
of our thematic shows ranveer Singh
talks about how there's a sport called
stand up paddle board yoga that means
people normally take a surfboard and
they go surfing right yeah yeah you know
it's it's very well known in Bondi Beach
in Australia and you know in in Miami
and things like that if you take a
surfboard and put it on still water and
try and do yoga on it the effect it has
on your core you know and apparently
people are taking vacations to the
Bahamas people are taking vacations to
the Maldives to do stand-up paddle board
yoga and stand up paddle board yoga
instructors do that bring yourself more
and do it on still water
you know and hold your core when it
comes to stand up and it comes to stand
up only I can think of his stand-up
comedy shows
but this is amazing you know this is uh
only ravi's got the core by which he can
do all this we have a long way to go
both of us need to start practicing for
me definitely okay we move now to the
the fun aspect of this interview and
part of the the great experience of just
hanging with you and chilling out with
you in studios is listening to your
immense experience of having met all
these wonderful Sports personalities
also sports that you follow very avidly
and of course your Marathon career I
want to start with
a WhatsApp message my eyes literally
popped out Sanjeev mantri Spain versus
Germany in Qatar oh my God
it's happened you know I was just so
happy I I lived through that game
through your eyes and I was watching it
on the television I said my Lord he's
there in the stadium that must have been
a goosebump inducing experience yeah so
uh absolutely and it was random luck uh
that you reached out it was actually a
meeting with redmi I think and that's
where I said that I would have loved to
catch up with him but the fact of the
matter is where I'm going is looking far
more relevant in scheme of things it was
an experience it was probably a bucket
list item and I did this uh with a
friend of mine who was crossing his 50th
so two uh 50 plus guys travel to Dua I
think it was electrified see any sports
activity if you are a sports buff gives
you Goosebumps when you see
people converting an activity to an art
and World Cup is the mecca right there's
nothing that goes beyond as far as
football is concerned uh
in the end but yes we're blessed to be
there we're happy to execute uh would
have loved meeting when we hopefully
Rishi will give me a time sometime or
the other and we'll make that happen but
an enthralling experience undoubtedly
and also the fact that you'd set
yourself a very clear goal saying you
want to finish these six marathons Tokyo
is was was bugging you and they were
like I have to do Tokyo to finish the
Tokyo marathon and it finally happened I
mean unfortunately you picked up an
injury on the way just talk to me about
that talk to me about training finally
what you felt in Japan finishing Tokyo
it's I think a very important question I
can probably speak on this for us
together but to keep it short and simple
uh March 20 is when we were supposed to
close this out March 3rd was the run and
uh that's how you know you plan but you
need your own luck and Destiny to
execute it pandemic happened couple of
weeks our training was all done and we
were supposed to just go run and that
would have taken care of all six major
marathons but life had planned something
else everything got canceled post that
it turned out to be an agonizing couple
of years wait uh you're right it was
annoying but and I picked up an injury
which made it even difficult but they
were friends who rally around you and
that's why you need friends probably
they really punched me or forced me into
it went through a rehab did uh my run
and when I was on the last kilometer
ah the feeling was more of relief that
it's done and dusted I want to move back
to tennis and probably spend some more
time learning and I'm still waiting for
a match or a game with you because
you've been phenomenal and you've I'm
sure can give me a lot more tips on how
to play My backend in tennis which
continues to be a pain but uh you know
whenever you do activities like this
this I ran my first of the sixth
marathon in 2011 in Berlin so it's taken
more than 10 years
sometimes but doing things slowly but
enjoying it is much better than probably
you know swallowing it very quickly and
I say what every minute of it it's gone
it's become part of a past now it looks
like a distant past also because my next
game is can I try do a triathlon and
that's what I'm eating for Rishi and
fingers crossed hopefully I'll do
something soon yeah you know when
Sanjeev told me off the mic he said you
know that's it I've done the marathon
circuit I suddenly thought of a random
thought came into my head you know
Sherpas the great Sherpas who used to
keep climbing Everest
they would climb Everest 10 times 15
times ready I was just okay it's not
going to happen yeah but it's one of
those things that just draws you you
know and you've got to keep doing it so
I'm glad that you might not do it in the
marathon form but you know long distance
running will continue with your attempts
at the triathlon so uh you know we wish
you great luck as far as that is
concerned personalities I mean I've I've
had these wonderful conversations with
you where you've talked about Kapil Dev
you've talked about bits of of your
interaction with Andre Agassi one of the
things that you do on a regular basis is
you motivate employees of icic Alone by
GIC to actually take part in the Mumbai
Marathon
um and you know get their Fitness levels
in check any personalities that you've
met off late a sporting personality or
otherwise that you've been pretty
impressed by so right now is rishiki one
of the best personalities I've met he's
given me a time after a long time and
has been absolute uh pleasure uh Frankly
Speaking the way I look at personalities
is anyone who can convert an ordinary
activity into an art so it's a panwala
outside Gallop so sets who makes amazing
pan to me to me he's worth worshiping
because see a lot of people do a lot of
stuff but the moment they take it to
next level in fact level which probably
I cannot see myself being I mean they
become part of my you know worship mode
where I really start enjoying it and you
see for me I easily fall into a
personality trap where you keep running
into people everywhere at every in every
Spirit of Life who are so much better is
part of the constraint and that's the
way I look at it but as of now if you
ask me recent path only personality I've
met worth mentioning is rishiki and no
one else that's so kind of you it was
really really so kind of guys get some
sun uh season seven I say I say low bar
presents get some sun season seven with
ranveer Singh with radio one radio host
as well as travel influencers comes to
you every single weekday morning
afternoon as well as evening on
Primetime radio please do follow it keep
an eye out on at 94.3 radio on India on
Instagram at uh look for our YouTube
channel at 943 radio one international
and of course the ICICI Lombard handles
across social media because there's also
a lot of Statics and videos that are
going out to celebrate this incredible
travel program that they have supported
icslombard and Sanjeev mantri are the
team have supported so kindly over the
years thank you very very much and I
can't wait to see you soon absolute
pleasure and thank you so much for
hosting me thank you so much thank you
thank you
94.3 radio 1.